Hi, and welcome to session four of learn and master guitar,
嗨，欢迎来到 learn and master guitar 第四课，
this time we're going to talk about the fifth and the sixth string,
这次我们要讲的是第五弦和第六弦，
we've already covered the first, second, third and fourth,
我们已经讲了一、二、三和四弦，
now we're up to the fifth and sixth,
现在我们到第五弦和第六弦，
going to look at them notes on those strings,
来看看这些弦上的音符，
once we conquer those,
一旦我们征服了那些，
we have conquered all the notes in the first position,
我们就征服了第一个位置上的所有音符，
that's what today is all about wrapping up all of our notes,
这就是今天我们要总结的所有音符，
we've learned two-thirds of them so far,
到目前为止，我们已经学习了三分之二的音符，
we've got one-third more of the notes to come,
我们还有三分之一的音符要学，
then we're going to put it all together,
然后我们把它们放在一起，
we also need to talk to you about sharps and flats,
我们还需要讨论升调和降调，
playing in different keys
使用不同的调演奏，
and we're going to learn two more chords,
我们将再学习两个和弦，
we are going to learn Am and E,
我们将学习 Am 和 E ，
so I hope you're ready to get started,
我希望你们准备好开始，
let's go ahead and have some fun.
让我们继续，并找到一些乐趣。
Now we're going to talk about the notes on the fifth string,
现在我们将讨论第五弦上的音符，
here's three more notes on the fifth string,
第五弦上有三个音符，
starts out with an open A,
从一个空弦 A 开始，
fifth string open is A,
第五弦的空弦是 A ，
play one more time, A.
再弹一次， A 。
Now you'll notice we're at two ledger lines deep underneath that staff,
现在你会注意到，我们在两个加线的深处，
guitar reads pretty low on the staff,
吉他的在乐谱上读数非常低，
we'll get as low as three ledger lines
我们会得到低至三个加线的音符，
and when we talk about the notes on the sixth string,
当我们谈到第六弦上的音符时，
but A that's two ledger lines down,
但是 A 是向下两个加线，
take a good look at it,
仔细看看它，
sometimes it might get confusing when we start adding those ledger lines,
有时当我们开始添加这些加线时，它可能会让人困惑，
but the more you do it, the better you'll get at it.
但你做得越多，你就会更好地理解它。
The second note on the fifth string is a B,
第五弦上的第二个音符是 B ，
with our second finger on the second fret,
我们的食指放在第二个品丝上，
here's a B
这里一个 B ，
okay, now you try and play with me, ready.
好的，现在你试着和我一起弹，准备。
Now the third note on that fifth string is a C,
现在，第五弦上的第三个音符是 C ，
we've learned A, we've learned B
我们已经学了 A ，我们已经学了 B ，
and now we're gonna learn C, third finger, third fret, C,
现在我们要学 C ，无名指，第三个品丝， C ，
ready, let's play together, C.
准备，让我们一起弹， C 。
Let's go through all the notes A, B and C.
让我们复习一下所有的音符， A B C 。
Alright, take a look at your fifth string exercises,
好的，看一下你的第五弦练习，
we're going to number one on that,
我们要做第一个，
we just work this out on those lower notes,
我们现在解决那些低音的问题，
now, as we're getting to these lower notes,
当我们到这些低音时，
make sure that your wrist is underneath the guitar,
确保你的手腕在吉他下面，
if your wrist is way up here,
如果你的手腕在这里，
then you're going to start running out of fingers,
那么你的手指会开始耗尽，
when we start when we start trying to play notes way down here on the neck,
当我们开始尝试在琴颈上向下演奏音符时，
you got to lower that risk,
你必须降低风险，
I know what you want to put this up,
我知道你想把这个放在上面，
that helps you with your hand strength,
这有助于你的手力量，
but you need to get these fingers stronger,
但你需要让这些手指更强壮，
so they need to do what they need to do
所以他们需要做他们需要做的事情，
and part of that is lowering that risk down a little bit,
其中之一是降低风险，
so keep that wrist nice and low,
所以保持手腕的足够低，
make sure you've got some air space right in here.
确保你在这里有一些空间。
Okay, as we go down for these low notes,
好的，让我们开始弹这些低音，
here we go, exercise number one,
我们开始，练习一，
lets play together, starts on that low A,
让我们一起弹奏，从那个低音 A 开始，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
A, second finger B,
A ，食指 B ，
now C, two three four,
现在 C 2 3 4 ，
C B A, good,
C B A ，好的，
A C A.
A C A 。
Very good, try one more time it's a little bit faster,
很好，再试一次会更快一点，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
A B C, two three four,
A B C ， 2 3 4 ，
C B A, there you go, A B A.
C B A ，继续， A B A 。
Good, alright, look at exercise number two,
好的，看第二个练习，
we'll slow it back down a little bit,
我们会把它放慢一点，
added some eighth notes into it,
在里面加一些第八个音符，
let's see if we can do this one.
让我们看看我们是否能做这个。
Ready, exercise number two,
准备，练习二，
ready, play, A A A,
准备，弹奏， A A A ，
let's do it again, do it again, A.
我们再来一次， A 。
Very good, okay, now let's learn the notes on the sixth string,
好的，现在让我们学习第六弦上的音符，
this is the last [] of notes that you need to learn here for a few minutes.
这是你需要学习的最后几个音符，花几分钟时间。
On the sixth string, we have open E,
在第六弦上，我们有空弦 E ，
three ledger lines down, that's as low as you go,
三个加线，这是最低的，
you don't get any lower than that on the guitar,
你不会比吉他上得到更低的，
three ledger lines down, that an E,
三个加线，这是 E ，
then first finger, F,
然后是食指 F ，
and third finger, G,
无名指 G ，
now wait a minute, we got E F and G,
等一下，我们得到了 E F G ，
just like on the first string,
就像第一弦一样，
we have open E F and G,
我们有空弦 E F G ，
the six string is an E as well,
第六弦也是 E ，
as we go E F G.
像这样， E F G 。
Okay, now that six string is a good bit thicker than all the rest of the strings,
好的，现在第六弦比所有其他弦都粗，
so you're really gonna have to push those fingers down,
所以你真的要把手指往下推，
give them a good workout doing these six string exercises,
让它们好好做第六弦练习，
it may be a little buzzy at first,
一开始可能有点嗡嗡作响，
may come out sound a little bit like that,
听起来可能有点像这样，
just work on that hand pressure a little bit,
只要手上稍微做加一点压力，
make sure you're doing all the right things,
确保你做的所有正确的事情，
hugging up right behind that fret
按在紧靠品丝后面，
and you'll get those notes to sound out clearly,
你会让那些音符发出清晰的声音，
even if it's buzzing out,
即使它嗡嗡作响，
you keep working at it
你继续努力，
and they'll get steadier and stronger.
它们会变得更稳定、更强劲。
Let's do those six string exercise,
我们来做这些第六弦练习，
we're going to start on that page exercise number three,
我们将从练习三开始，
ready, we'll go nice and slow,
准备，我们会慢一点，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
E F G,
E F G ，
G F E,
G F E ，
now some eighth notes, down up,
现在是一些八分音符，下上，
pretty good, let's try one more time,
很好，让我们再试一次，
ready, go.
准备，开始。
Alright, now let's put all of the notes together,
好的，现在让我们把所有的音符放在一起，
everything that we've learned so far
到目前为止我们学到的所有东西，
and do exercise number four,
做练习四，
look at all those eighth notes,
看所有的八分音符，
we're going to take it pretty slow,
我们会非常慢，
okay, we're just gonna go through all these notes one by one.
好的，我们将一个接一个地弹奏所有这些音符。
Ready, starts down on low E,
准备，从低音 E 开始，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
E F G A B C D E F G A B C D E F G, G, G
E F G A B C D E F G A B C D E F G ， G ， G ，
and now we're gonna head back down, you ready,
现在我们往下了，你准备好了吗，
G F E D C B A G F E D C B A G F E.
G F E D C B A G F E D C B A G F E 。
Very good, those are the notes we've learned on the fifth and sixth string,
很好，这些是我们在第五弦和第六弦上学到的音符，
fifth string A B and C,
第五弦 A B C ，
six string E F and G.
第六弦 E F G 。
Let's review all of our first position notes,
让我们回顾一下所有的第一把位音符，
when I mean, when I say first position,
当我说第一个把位时，
I mean down here on this end of the guitar,
我指的是这个吉他位置的下面，
position, when I say position, that refers to your fret that you're on,
当我说把位时，指的是你的品丝，
sometimes you'll be in the fifth position,
有时你会在第五把位，
that means you start your hand on the fifth position, on the fifth fret,
意思是开始你的手在第五把位，第五品丝，
its third position, you'd start your hand and you do your fingers,
在第三把位，你应该开始你的手，使你的手指，
remember, first finger, second finger, third finger, pinky, covers both,
记得，食指，中指，无名指，小指，所覆盖的，
that would be like a position that would be in third,
这将是第三把位，
but we're going to be down in first position
但我们将下降到第一个位置，
and that's where we've learned all of our notes.
这是我们学习所有音符的地方。
Okay, so let's review one more time,
好的，让我们再复习一次，
on the sixth string, we've got E F and G,
在第六弦上，我们有 E F G ，
E F G,
E F G ，
on the fifth string A B and C,
在第五弦上， A B C ，
A B C,
A B C ，
the fourth string, we've got D E F,
在第四弦上，我们有 D E F ，
the third string, we've got G and A,
第三弦上，我们有 G 和 A ，
second string, we've got B C and D,
第二弦上，我们有 B C D ，
E F and G.
E F G 。
Okay, now we're gonna go down backwards,
好的，现在我们要往后退，
try not to look at the music,
试着不要看乐谱，
want you to just look at your hands,
希望你只看你的手，
or just think about what these notes are,
或者只是想着这些音符是什么，
as we play them down,
当我们演奏它们的时候，
give them insight internalize these notes
洞察这些音符，内化这些音符，
rather than just reading them off the page,
而不是仅仅从纸上读出它们，
I want you to understand where they're at,
我想让你们理解它们在哪里，
try not to look at the music,
试着不要看乐谱，
let's just go down backwards,
让我们倒退回去，
say the notes, while you're playing them.
当你演奏的时候，说出音符。
Ready,
准备，
G F E D C B A G F E D C B A G F E,
G F E D C B A G F E D C B A G F E ，
very good.
非常好。
Okay, now, let's go,
好的，现在我们开始，
if you look at your first position note exercise,
如果你看你的第一把位音符练习，
we're going do number one,
我们将弹第一个，
we're going to climb up basically a C scale
我们将攀升一个 C 音阶，
and we haven't learned about scales yet,
我们还没有学习到音阶，
but it is a C scale
但它是一个 C 音阶，
and it starts on fifth string, third fret, that's C.
它从第五弦，第三品开始，这是 C 。
Ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
and it goes back down,
然后它又会往下走，
very good, let's play a little bit faster now,
很好，现在让我们弹快一点，
ready.
准备。
There you go,
弹得不错，
now we're gonna do one more exercise,
现在我们再做一个练习，
that incorporates all the notes that we've learned so far,
把我们目前学到的所有音符结合起来，
Minuet in C,
C 大调小步舞步，
take a look at that in your books, open that up,
看一下在你们的书里，把它打开，
let's go through that slowly one time.
让我们慢慢来一遍。
Here we go,
我们开始，
ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
one two,
1 2 ，
two three,
2 3 ，
very good.
非常好。
Okay, now we need to talk about one more concept,
好的，现在我们需要再谈一个概念，
sharps and flats,
升调和降调，
now I'm sure you've been wondering,
现在我相信你一定在想，
we've got, on this first string, we've got open, first and third,
在第一弦上，我们有空弦、第一品和第三品，
but what about what's this note in between,
但是那个之间的这个音符是什么，
what's that note,
那个音符是什么，
well, just like there are black keys and white keys on a piano,
好的，就像钢琴上有黑键和白键一样，
each of them being a half-step apart,
每个键都相隔半音，
a guitar every fret that you see on the neck is exactly one half-step
吉他，你在琴颈上看到的每一个音符都是一个半音，
and different notes
不同的音符
either have a half-step in between them
要么在它们之间有半音，
or don't have a half-step in between them,
要么在它们之间没有半音，
half and whole steps is, what this is called,
半音和全音是，
when you have two half-steps put together makes up a whole step,
当你把两个半音放在一起，就组成一个全音，
but each of these is one half-step apart,
但是每一个音符都有半音之隔，
so let's now we're going to talk about the notes that are in between the notes.
所以现在我们来讨论一下音符之间的音符。
There's two ways to look at them,
有两种方式来看它们，
let's talk about sharps first,
让我们来先谈谈升调，
the little number sign looking symbol is a sharp sign,
这个小的像数字符号的符号是一个升调的符号，
what that means is,
它的意思是，
it takes whatever note that you is in front of it,
它记下了你的任何音符。
you see the sharp sign,
你看到升调符号，
you raise that note up one half step, one fret worth on your guitar,
你在吉他上把音符提高半音，一品，
and that's what sharps do,
这就是升调所做的，
you've learned all the notes so far,
到目前为止，你已经学会了所有的音符，
now we're just going to adjust those notes a little bit using sharps and flats,
现在我们只需要用升调和降调来调整这些音符，
let's look at the sharp line first,
让我们先看看升调，
we're going to start on this F, first finger f,
我们将从这个 F 开始，食指 F ，
now remember finger rule supply,
现在记住手指规则，
so when I go to this F#, which would be right here,
当我到这个 #F 时，它在这里，
my second finger would cover that,
我的中指将覆盖它，
first finger covers everything in the first fret on all strings,
食指覆盖所有弦上第一品的所有东西，
second covers anything on the second,
中指覆盖第二品的所有，
third covers anything on the third,
无名指覆盖第三品上所有，
pinky pulls double duty,
小指有两个任务，
anything that happens on the fourth or the fifth, pinky covers.
小指覆盖在第四个或第五个发生的任何事情。
So we have F and now we've got F#,
所以我们有 F ，现在我们有 #F ，
okay, and we've got G and then we've got G#,
好的，我们有 G ，然后我们有 #G ，
on this next string,
在下一个弦上，
we would have a C,
我们有一个 C ，
then a C# with our second finger,
然后用我们的食指 #C ，
D, then a D# with our pinky,
D ，然后一个 #D ，使用我们的小指，
good.
好的。
On the third string, we would have open G,
在第三弦上，我们有空弦 G ，
now how do I sharpen open string,
现在我如何对空弦升调，
well, you put your first finger on that string,
你把你的食指放在那根弦上，
and that would be a G#, there,
那就是 #G ，这样，
okay, so we have G, we've got G#,
好的，所以我们有 G ，我们有 #G ，
second finger would be A,
中指将是 A ，
after that would be an A#,
在那之后，将是 #A ，
okay, on the fourth string,
好的，在第四弦上，
we have D,
我们有 D ，
how did we sharpen open string,
我们如何对空弦升调，
put our first finger on that first fret, D#,
把我们的食指放在第一品上， #D ，
and E, oh, here's our first problem,
E ，哦，这是我们的第一个问题，
if I wanted an E#,
如果我想要一个 #E ，
that would be on the third fret,
它将在第三品，
but that's already an F, you're probably saying to yourself,
但已经是一个 F ，你可能会对自己说，
you're exactly right,
你完全正确，
and E# is an F,
#E 就是 F ，
F is the more common name,
F 是更常见的名字，
so you hardly ever hear it referred to as an E#,
所以你很少听到它被称为 #E ，
but I guess technically it would be an E#,
但我猜从技术上讲，它应该是 #E ，
there is F, where an F#,
这是 F ，哪里是 #F ，
we got our pinky over here.
我们把小指放在这里。
The fifth string got open A,
第五弦的空弦是 A ，
if I wanted A#, it will be there,
如果我需要 #A ，它将在这里，
B, then B# or more commonly known to a C,
B ，然后 #B 或者更常见的是 C ，
then C#.
然后 #C 。
On the last string,
在最后一根弦上，
let's just start on the F,
我们从 F 开始，
second finger F#,
食指， #F ，
third finger G, G#,
无名指 G ， #G ，
see how those work sharps,
看到这些升调是如何工作的，
sharps go up a half-step.
升调向上半音。
Now let's talk about the opposite way,
现在我们来谈谈相反的方式，
I can take a note up a half-step,
我可以把音符上升半音，
but I can also take a note and bring it down a half-step
但我也可以拿一个音符，然后把它降低半音，
and those are called flats,
那就称为降调，
when it is a flat, that's that little b,
当它是降调的时候，它是一个小写 b ，
it looks like a [] b,
它看起来是一个[]b ，
that's a flat sign,
这是一个降调符号，
when you see that by a note,
当你看到它在一个音符后面，
you play the note a half step down
你演奏的音符降低半音，
from where we had done initially,
从我们最初所做的，
if it were just plain,
如果它是简单的，
okay, so let's do a few of these.
好的，我们来做几个这样的。
Starts out on a G,
从 G 开始，
now if I want a Gb,
如果我想要 bG ，
I would not go up this way,
我不会走这个方向，
I wouldn't go this way on the neck,
我不会走琴颈上这个方向，
I would go back down this way,
我会走这个方向，
what should be a Gb,
应该是 bG ，
got it, G, Gb,
明白了吗， G ， bG ，
now wait a minute, where was that F# that we learned a little bit ago,
现在等一下，我们刚才学到的那个 #F 在哪里，
F, F#,
F ， #F ，
F# and Gb are the same note,
#F 和 bG 是同一个音符，
you're just looking at it from different perspectives,
你只是从不同的角度来看它，
if I'm on F,
如果我在 F 上，
I would look up there would be an F#,
我会向上看，那是 #F ，
if I met a G,
如果我遇到 G ，
I'm looking down on it, flat it, it would be a Gb,
我向下看，对它降调，它将是 bG ，
so when you get into these sharps and flats notes,
所以当你进入这些升调和降调音符，
a lot of times, they'll have you come out from either direction,
很多次，它们会从任何一个方向出来，
so you have two names for the same note.
所以你有两个名字代表同一个音符。
So we have G, we have Gb,
所以我们有 G ，我们有 bG ，
then we have f,
然后我们有 F ，
go down the next open,
下一个空弦，
and here's our first problem,
这是我们的第一个问题，
how do I flat an open string,
我如何对空弦降调，
I can't get any lower than open string,
我不能得到比空弦更低的，
the rule says you go down to the next string,
规则是，你到下一根弦，
which would be the second string and use your pinky,
也就是第二弦，然后用你的小指，
so, so that would be an Eb,
所以，那就是 bE ，
the rule is you go down to the next string and use your pinky,
规则是，你到下一根弦，用你的小指，
so here's a E, here's an Eb,
所以，这是 E ，这是 bE ，
let's keep going, D, Db,
我们继续， D ， bD ，
C, then B.
C ，然后 B 。
Okay, here's the one exception to the rule here I just taught you rule
好的，这是我刚刚教给你们的规则的一个例外，
and this is going to be the one exception to the rule.
这是这个规则的一个例外。
On the third string,
在第三弦上，
just has to do with how the guitar is tuned
与吉他是如何调音的，
and how it's been tuned [over the ages],
以及它是如何[随着岁月的推移]的而调弦的，
a Bb, which is what we're going for
bB ，这就是我们想要的，
would not be with your pinky,
不会是你的小指，
which is what the rule would say,
这就是规则说，
this is the one exception,
这是一个例外，
a Bb is with your third finger,
bB 是用你的无名指，
B, Bb,
B ， bB ，
A, Ab, G,
A ， bA ， G ，
now we're back to our rule again,
现在我们又回到我们的规则，
how do we flatten open string,
我们如何对空弦降调，
fourth, we go the fourth finger, the next string down Gb,
我们用小指，下一根弦上 bG ，
F, E, Eb, D,
F E bE D ，
let's keep going, Db C B Bb A,
让我们继续， bD C B bB A ，
Ab, G, we're giving our pinky a good workout, Gb and F.
bA G ，我们使用小指工作， bG F 。
Very good, and that's sharps and flats.
很好，那就是升调和降调。
Okay, one more concept,
好的，还有一个概念，
I need to tell you about in sharps and flats,
我需要告诉你们关于升调和降调，
sharps and flats have a time duration on them,
升调和降调是有持续时间的，
time duration what that means is
持续时间意味着，
they are good for one measure,
它们对于一个小节是好的，
so if you look in your example there,
所以如果你看一下这里的例子，
an F going to an F#,
F 变成 #F ，
once I sharp that F,
一旦我对那个 F 升调，
then that F is sharp for the rest of the measure,
那么在小节中剩下的部分中， F 都是升调的，
no matter whether it's high F, low F, or media F,
不管它是高音 F 还是低音 F ，或者中音 F ，
you know whatever F, as soon as one F sharp, all Fs are sharp
任何 F ，只要一个 F 升调，所有的 F 都会升调，
for the complete rest of the measure,
在整个小节剩下的部分中，
once I hit that bar line,
一旦我达到小节线，
then it resets again,
它就会再次重置，
now, what if I get to that second F#
现在，如果我到达第二个 #F ，
and I really don't want it to be an F#,
我不希望它是 #F ，
how can I cancel it out,
我怎么才能取消它，
that's where you use a natural sign,
那就是你用自然符号的地方，
a natural sign looks like kind of two Ls backed up against each other,
自然符号看起来像是两个 L 相互抵挡，
that cancels out a previously held sharp or flat.
它取消了之前保持的升调或降调。
We're going to learn two chords today,
我们今天学习两个和弦，
we're going to learn Am and an E.
我们将学习 Am 和 E 。
The m standing next to the standing next to A, that's the minor,
A 旁边的那个 m ，它是小调，
it's a symbol for minors, Am.
它是小调的符号， Am 。
Let's go through it,
让我们来看一遍，
let's take a look at Am,
让我们来看看 Am ，
there's nothing happening on the sixth string,
第六弦上什么都没发生，
the fifth string is open,
第五弦是空弦，
on the fourth string, you have your second finger,
在第四弦上，使用你的中指，
third string, you have your third finger down there on the second fret,
第三弦，你把无名指放在第二品上，
first finger on that C
食指在 C 上，
and the last string is open.
最后一个是空弦。
I played them in each note individually would sound like this,
我弹奏每个音符听起来像这样，
one more time,
再来一次，
altogether,
一起，
that's Am chord.
这是 Am 和弦。
Now an E chord has exactly the same finger shape,
E 和弦也有完全相同的手指形状，
if you just move everybody up a whole string set,
如果你把每个手指抬起来，
just move everybody up the whole string set
把每个手指移动一个弦，
and you end up with an E chord,
最后得到一个 E 和弦，
that a six string chord, use all six strings,
它是一个六个弦的和弦，使用所有六根弦，
that it individually.
让我们分别弹一下。
Now let's go through your two exercises, your three exercises there,
现在让我们来看看你的两三个练习，
exercise one goes from between the Am and the E,
练习一在 Am 和 E 之间，
it just practices jumping you between those two chords.
它只是练习在这两个和弦之间切换。
Here we go, Am,
我们开始， Am ，
ready play, two three,
准备，弹奏， 2 3 ，
now an E, two, three,
现在是 E ， 2 3 ，
back to the Am,
回到 Am ，
back to E,
回到 E ，
and it ends up on that Am.
最后回到 Am 。
Okay, exercise number two,
好的，练习二，
starts with a C,
从 C 开始，
we're going to combine some of our other chords, that we've already had,
我们将结合我们已经掌握的其他和弦，
remember we had the C, the G7,
记得我们有 C ， G7 ，
and now we are adding the Am and E.
现在，我们添加 Am 和 E 。
Let's do exercise number two,
让我们做练习二，
one two, ready, go,
1 2 ，准备，开始，
Am,
Am ，
here comes E
这是 E ，
G7
G7 ，
C.
C 。
Okay, on exercise three,
好的，在练习三中，
I throw them in there together,
我把它们放在一起，
they're all mixed up together,
它们都混在一起，
but they change a little bit faster,
但它们变化得更快，
I'll take this one pretty slow for you.
我会为你们慢慢来。
Exercise number three,
练习三，
ready, C chord,
准备， C 和弦，
now Am chord,
现在是 Am 和弦，
G7, for four beats, two three four,
G7 四拍， 2 3 4 ，
open E one two,
E ， 1 2 ，
Am
Am ，
and a C chord.
和 C 和弦。
Very good.
非常好。
Now let's talk about your assignment for this session,
现在让我们来讨论一下你在这节课上的作业，
session four,
第四节课，
what I want you to do is
因为我想让你做的是
all of the notes in the first position.
第一把位上的所有音符。
Go through, sing and play all the way from low E up to high G,
通过唱和演奏从低音 E 到高音 G ，
sing and play,
唱和演奏，
trying to do with the music,
试着使用乐谱，
try to do without the music and just memorize them.
试着不使用乐谱，只是记住它们。
There's also some notes in the first position exercises there,
在第一把位练习中还有一些音符，
that I'd like for you to cover,
我想让你们掌握，
we're also going to cover three songs,
我们还将学习三首歌曲，
are biggest songs yet,
它们都是很棒的歌曲，
Simple Gifts, Minuet in G, and The Star Spangled Banner.
简单的礼物， G 大调小步舞步，星条旗之歌。
So work on those and we can work on them together in the workshop time.
所以，我们可以在 workshop 时间一起研究这些。
Now let me talk about some guitar tips,
现在让我谈谈一些吉他技巧，
in the guitar tips section today,
在今天的吉他技巧部分，
I wanted to just cover, I didn't want to cover any material,
我不想涵盖任何材料，
but I just want to encourage you,
但我想鼓励你，
if you're serious about guitar playing,
如果你对弹吉他是认真的，
what you need to do is work hard at it,
你需要做的就是努力学习，
I can present it to you in a fairly short amount of time,
我可以在相当短的时间内把它呈现给你，
but you will only get better with the effort that you put into it,
但你只会通过投入的努力变得更好，
and a little bit of effort,
还有一点努力，
it's the guys that put slow consistent effort into it
那些投入缓慢而持续的努力的人
are the ones that actually end up playing guitar at the end of the day,
才是真正有一天弹吉他的人，
it's not the guys that always dream about guitar playing
而不是那些总是梦想着弹吉他
or hang around guitar players or anything like that,
或和吉他演奏者呆在一起或类似的事情，
those aren't the ones that actually get the job done,
这些人并不是真正完成工作的人，
I've been teaching for years
我教书多年了，
and I've been playing for years and years and years
我弹奏了很多年，
and I have not found another way to get better
但一直没有找到更好的方法
other than good old hard work sitting on your couch, sitting on your bed, doing simple exercises,
除了坐在沙发上、床上做简单的练习之外，
you may feel like why am I doing these dopey little tunes,
你可能会觉得，为什么我要做这些愚蠢的小调，
what I really want to be playing great stuff,
我想要演奏伟大的东西，
I have not found another shortcut to be able to do it
我还没有找到其他的捷径，
other than working hard,
除了努力练习，
so I just encourage you,
所以我只是鼓励你，
if you've made it this far in this series,
如果你在这一系列中走到了这一步，
you're obviously serious about what you're doing
你显然对你所做的事情是认真的，
and I would encourage you to keep it up,
我会鼓励你继续下去，
we've finished through the single notes
我们已经完成了单音符，
and we're getting ready to start into chords,
我们准备开始进入和弦，
which is kind of another hemisphere of guitar playing
这是吉他演奏的另一个半球，
and you're getting ready to come into some fun stuff,
你准备进入一些有趣的东西，
but your hard work here and diligence will pay off.
但你在这里的辛勤工作和勤奋将得到回报。
Hey, welcome session four guitar workshop,
嗨，欢迎来到第四课的吉他 workshop ，
here's where we get the job done,
这是我们完成工作的地方，
here's where we really get the skills that we need to get done,
这是我们真正获得完成所需技能的地方，
you're ready, let's practice,
你准备好了，让我们练习，
first thing we need to do is
我们需要做的第一件事是
review all of our notes that we've gone through so far,
复习我们到目前为止已经做过的所有音符，
so we're starting on that low E,
所以我们从低音 E 开始，
let's go through them and let's play and sing together,
让我们一起弹奏和唱，
you ready?
你准备好了吗？
E F G A B C D E F G A B C D E F G,
E F G A B C D E F G A B C D E F G ，
go down backwards,
回退，
G, D C B A G F E D C.
G ， D C B A G F E D C 。
Let's go through those one more time,
让我们再来一遍，
a little bit faster,
稍微快一点，
ready play,
准备，弹奏，
back down,
后退，
make sure your fingers are moving just like a machine,
确保你的手指像机器一样移动，
just coming on and off just like you want them to,
就像你想要的那样，
when they're not playing something,
当它们不演奏的时候，
they should be hovering right above the fret board.
它们应该在音板上方悬停。
Okay, now let's go through all of your notes one more time,
好的，现在让我们再弹一遍所有的音符，
this time we're gonna go pretty fast,
这一次我们会弹得很快，
see if you can keep up.
看你能不能跟上。
Ready play,
准备，演奏，
one more time.
再来一次。
Okay, now let's do a couple of exercises,
好的，现在让我们做几个练习，
if you look at your fifth and sixth string exercise sheet,
如果你看第五弦和第六弦练习表，
we're going to look at number four on that sheet,
我们将看看第四个，
so let's do that,
让我们来做这个，
number four on the fifth string, fifth and sixth string exercise sheet,
第五弦和第六弦练习表的第四个，
you ready, let's play,
你准备好了吗，我们来弹，
ready, go,
准备，开始，
G G G,
G G G ，
now you go back down.
现在你再回退，
There you go, now, we also learned two chords,
干得好，现在，我们还学习了两个和弦，
we learned an Am and an E,
我们学习了 Am 和 E ，
let's review those,
让我们复习一下，
here's an Am,
这是 Am ，
here's an E,
这是 E ，
let's play four Ams and four Es,
让我们弹奏四个 Am 和四个 E ，
go,
开始，
one more time,
再来一次，
four Ams,
四个 Am ，
E,
E ，
Am, two three four.
Am ， 2 3 4 。
Very good, we also learned about sharps and flats,
很好，我们还学习了升调和降调，
remember sharps, sharps take, not sharks, but sharps,
记得升调，不是鲨鱼，而是升调，
sharps take whatever note you're playing and you raise it up a half step,
无论你演奏什么音符，升调将它提高半音，
one fret worth on the guitar.
在吉他上就是一品。
Remember our exercise that we did,
还记得我们的练习吗，
let's go through a couple of those,
我们做的了几个，
on the first string F,
在第一弦上 F ，
then F# would be with our second finger,
然后 #F 是我们的中指，
G, G#.
G #G 。
On the second string,
在第二弦上，
C C#, D and D#.
C #C ， D #D 。
And we have open G,
我们有空弦 G ，
how do we sharpen open string,
如何对空弦升调，
with our first finger G#,
使用我们的食指 #G ，
A, A#.
A #A 。
Next string D, D#, E, E# or F, then F#.
下一个弦 D #D ， E #E 或者 F ，然后 #F 。
Open A, A# B C C#.
空弦 A ， #A锋利的B、C、E。
Open E, F F# G and G#.
空弦 E ， F #F G #G 。
Now, remember flats go the opposite way,
记得，降调朝相反的方向，
instead of going up a half step,
不是往上半步，
which would be this way on the neck,
在琴颈上这个方向，
they go down a half step,
它们往下走，
which would be going the opposite way.
也就是相反的方向。
So if we started on this G,
所以，如果我们从这个 G 开始，
it'd be G Gb F E,
它将是 G bG F E ，
remember our rule,
记得我们的规则，
how do we flatten open string,
我们如何对空弦降调，
go to the next string down, use a pinky,
到下一根弦上，使用小拇指，
Eb D Db C B,
bE D bD C B ，
here's the one that's different,
这里是不同的那个，
third finger on the Bb,
无名指在 bB 上，
A Ab G,
A bA G ，
Gb F E Eb D,
bG F E bE D ，
Db C B Bb A,
bD C B bB A ，
Ab G Gb and F.
bA G bG F 。
Okay, now we need to cover a couple of songs,
好的，现在我们需要介绍几首歌曲，
the songs that I asked you to play were
我让你们演奏的歌曲是
The Star Spangled Banner Banner, Minuet and Simple Gifts,
星条旗之歌，小步舞曲和简单的礼物，
we're going to start with The Star Spangled Banner,
我们将从星条旗之歌开始，
so go ahead and get that out.
所以继续，把它拿出来。
Let's take a look at this.
让我们来看看这个。
We're in three four time,
我们现在是三四拍，
now you'll notice the first two notes are just two eighth notes
你会注意到前两个音符只是两个八分音符，
and it's not even a full measure,
它甚至不是一个完整的小节，
those are called pickup notes,
这些被称为[拾音音符]，
they occur actually before the first full measure of music,
它们出现在第一个完整的音节之前，
it's quite a common thing in music,
这在音乐中是很常见的事情，
you just play those and don't worry about them,
你只要演奏，不要担心它们，
just play as if they were coming right into that first beat,
就像它们在第一节之前，
you ready, here we go.
你准备好了吗，我们开始。
One, play,
1 ，弹奏，
F# with your pinky,
用你的小拇指弹 #F ，
here you go,
继续，
two,
2 ，
one two, here comes F# again,
1 2 ，这里又是  #F ，
one two,
1 2 ，
F# G two.
#F G 2 。
Now you'll notice,
现在你会注意到，
in the last measure,
在最后一个小节中，
you have a half note,
你有一个半音符，
where's it should have three beats in it,
其中应该有三拍，
where's the other beat,
另一拍在哪里，
that makes up for where those pickups came in,
那就是弥补了拾音音符的位置，
if there's a partial measure at the beginning,
如果在开头有一个部分小节，
there's going to be a partial measure at the end,
在结尾会有一个部分小节，
truncate it,
截断它，
so that they both match up to make a full measure,
这样它们就会匹配成完整的小节，
why they do that,
他们为什么要这样做，
I don't know why they do that,
我不知道他们为什么要这样做，
that's kind of how it is.
这就是这样。
Let's play The Star Spangled Banner one more time,
让我们再来弹一次星条旗之歌，
this time a little bit faster up to tempo,
这一次，节奏稍微快一点，
now you'll notice the rhythm is slightly different from how we sing it,
现在你会注意到节奏与我们唱的略有不同，
that's because we haven't quite got to some of the more complex rhythms yet
这是因为我们还没有掌握一些更复杂的节奏，
of which Star Spangled Banner has in it
星条旗之歌包含在其中，
and are more common vocal version of it,
而是更常见的人声版本，
so just bear with us,
所以请耐心等待，
if you want to throw this in,
如果你想把这一点放进来，
you're more than welcome to,
很欢迎，
we're going to pick it up a little bit
我们将继续学习，
and do it one more time.
再来一次。
Ready, go,
准备，开始，
little bit of a pause there,.
这里稍作停顿，
See how I just did the rhythm a little bit to be more like our vocal version of it.
看到我只是做了一点节奏，让它更像我们的声乐版本。
Okay, now let's take a look at Simple Gifts,
好的，现在让我们来看看简单的礼物，
now you'll notice,
你会注意到，
in this one there's a sharp sign way up at the very beginning,
在这一开始有一个明显的升调标志，
it's not even by a note or anything,
它甚至不是由音符或任何东西，
that's called a key signature,
这被称为调号，
we'll talk more about those later,
我们稍后会更多地讨论这些，
but all this means,
但所有这些都意味着，
kind of a global setting on your computer,
类似在你的计算机上的一种全局设置，
once that there's a sharp sign over that F,
一旦一个升调符号在 F 上，
that means that every f in the entire song,
这意味着整首歌中的每个 F ，
whether high medium or low is going to be sharp,
无论是高、中还是低，都将是升调的，
and it doesn't even have to have a sharp sign by it,
它甚至不需要有升调的符号，
once that sharp sign is up in the key signature right up at the front of the song,
一旦调号在歌曲的前面，
that means every F you see is going to be an F#,
这意味着每一个你看到的 F 的将是 #F ，
okay, whether it's high medium or low, okay.
无论是高、中、低，好的。
So here we go,
所以我们开始，
let's do Simple Gifts,
让我们弹简单的礼物，
got a pickup note again,
又有一个拾音音符，
here we go, ready, play,
我们开始，准备，弹奏，
here comes an F#,
这是一个 #F ，
keep going, one two,
继续， 1 2 ，
Very good, very traditional song.
非常好，非常传统的歌曲。
Now we're going to play through it one more time,
现在我们再弹一次，
but I particularly want to work with you,
但我特别想和你们一起来讨论，
on that one measure, what is that the fourth measure of that song,
在一个小节中，这首歌的第四个小节是什么，
it has an F# in it.
它有一个 #F 。
Okay, let's just do that measure
好的，让我们做这个小节，
and work on it slowly,
慢慢地做，
we'll do it a couple times,
我们会做几次，
then we'll play the whole song again,
然后我们会再次弹奏整首歌曲，
so in that measure four,
所以在第四小节中，
it goes starts on A,
它是从 A 开始的，
do one more time,
再来一次，
a little bit faster.
快一点。
Very good, okay, just play Simple Gifts one more time,
很好，好的，再弹一次简单的礼物，
I'll do it a little bit faster now,
我现在会快一点，
so you can keep up.
这样你就可以跟上。
Ready, go.
准备，开始。
There you go, that's Simple Gifts,
干得好，这是简单的礼物，
now the next one we need to cover is Minuet.
现在我们需要介绍的下一个是小步舞曲。
Okay, let's take a look at Minuet in G,
好的，让我们来看看 G 大调小步舞曲，
that G is referring to keys,
那个 G 指的是调，
which we'll learn a little bit more about later,
我们稍后会更多地了解它，
but look it also has that F# up in the corner,
但看到它的角上也有 #F ，
so what does that mean,
那么它是什么意思，
all the Fs are going to be sharp.
所有 F 都会升调。
Okay, so let's go ahead and try and play it nice and slow,
好的，让我们继续，试着慢慢地演奏，
you'll probably recognize the melody.
你可能会听出旋律。
Ready, play,
准备，弹奏，
here comes F#, there you go,
这是 #F ，干得好，
here's another F#,
这是另一个 #F ，
F#,
#F ，
one last F#, two three, next page,
最后一个 #F ， 2 3 ，下一页，
here comes a C# with our second finger,
这里是一个 #C 使用我们的中指，
dotted half note, two three,
加点的二分音符， 2 3 ，
this is a little tricky here,
这里有点棘手，
two three.
2 3 。
Okay, that's going through it, kind of slow,
好的，这是有点慢，
let's see if we can play it a little bit faster now.
让我们看看现在能不能再快一点。
You ready,
你准备好了吗，
remember those F#,
记得那些 #F ，
there's also that C# in there.
这里还有 #C 。
Here we go, ready, play,
我们开始，准备，弹奏，
two three.
2 3 。
Very, very good,
非常，非常好，
okay remember, remember your practice schedule,
好的，记住你的练习时间表，
if you can be putting in fifteen to twenty minutes five out of seven days a week,
如果你一周七天中有五天能投入 15 到 20 分钟，
that is about the time span you need to make good progress with all this,
那就是你需要的一段时间，
guitar playing can be a rich and rewarding skill
吉他演奏是一项丰富而有回报的技能，
and effort will help you improve,
努力将帮助你提高，
so keep working hard at it
所以继续努力，
and I'll see you next time.
我们下次再见。